https://matomo.org/privacy-policy/#optout

Skip to content
Menu
MENUMENUWhy Matomo?
100% Data OwnershipPrivacy ProtectionProduct FeaturesOpen SourceFlexibilityNo Data SamplingGDPRGoogle Analytics Alternative
Use Cases
Complete AnalyticsIntranet AnalyticsAvoid Consent ScreensTracking Personal DataNo limitationsLog Analytics
On-Premise
Matomo On-PremiseOn-Premise vs CloudDownload for freeMarketplaceSupport Plans
PricingResources
HelpIntegrationsContact the Matomo teamList of all featuresGet involvedDemo
TRY IT FOR FREE
Privacy Policy
We believe in openness, privacy and 100% data ownership. Matomo’s mission is to liberate analytics and we are passionate about measuring for success. These core values are ingrained into everything we do here at Matomo and that will never change.
This Policy describes the information we collect from you, how we use that information and our legal basis for doing so. It also covers whether and how that information may be shared and your rights and choices regarding the information you provide to us.
This Privacy Policy applies to the information that we obtain through your use of Matomo websites including its subdomains demo.matomo.cloud, forum.matomo.org, developer.matomo.org, shop.matomo.org, plugins.matomo.org, ios.matomo.org, issues.matomo.org, glossary.matomo.org.
Matomo Cloud Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy does not cover the Matomo Cloud-hosted service by InnoCraft where the  Matomo Cloud (InnoCraft) Privacy Policy applies.
Who we are
Matomo is an open source project brought to you by the Matomo team members as well as many other contributors around the globe.
Matthieu Aubry is the legal representative of the Matomo project. If you have any questions about this privacy policy, please contact our privacy team at privacy@matomo.org
We will never sell your personal data to anyone.
What We Collect and Receive
In order for us to provide you the best possible experience on our websites, we need to collect and process certain information. Depending on your use of the Services, that may include:
Contact us via email — for example, when you ask for support, send us questions or comments, or report a problem, we will collect your name, email address, message, etc. We use this data solely in connection with answering the queries we receive.
Usage data — when you visit our site, we will store: the website from which you visited us from, the parts of our site you visit, the date and duration of your visit, your anonymised IP address, information from the device (device type, operating system, screen resolution, language, country you are located in, and web browser type) you used during your visit, and more. We process this usage data in Matomo Analytics for statistical purposes, to improve our site and to recognize and stop any misuse.
Cookies — we use cookies (small data files transferred onto computers or devices by sites) for record-keeping purposes and to enhance functionality on our site. You may deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings of your web browser. Cookies that are already stored may be deleted at any time.
Create an account — when you sign up for and open an account on our forum, or purchase a premium plugin on the Matomo Marketplace, or sign up for content or offers, we may ask you to provide us with information such as your name, email address and details about your organization. As otherwise detailed in this Privacy Policy, we will solely process this information to provide you with the service you signed up for.
Opt-out of website tracking
You can opt out of being tracked by our Matomo Analytics instance below:
Your Rights
You have the right to be informed of Personal Data processed by Matomo, a right to rectification/correction, erasure and restriction of processing. You also have the right to ask from us a structured, common and machine-readable format of Personal Data you provided to us.
We can only identify you via your email address and we can only adhere to your request and provide information if we have Personal Data about you through you having made contact with us directly and/or you using our site and/or service. We cannot provide, rectify or delete any data that we store on behalf of our users or customers.
To exercise any of the rights mentioned in this Privacy Policy and/or in the event of questions or comments relating to the use of Personal Data you may contact Matomo’s support team: privacy@matomo.org
In addition, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data protection authority in your jurisdiction.
Subprocessors
We use a select number of trusted external service providers for certain technical data processing and/or service offerings. These service providers are carefully selected and meet high data protection and security standards. We only share information with them that is required for the services offered and we contractually bind them to keep any information we share with them as confidential and to process Personal Data only according to our instructions.
Matomo uses the following subprocessors to process the data collected by our websites:
Subprocessor
Data location and security
Service
AlwaysData
Europe, France
Secure infrastructure for servers and databases and logs hosted in Paris, France.
Third party services we use
When you visit our websites, or purchase products or services, we use the following third party services which may collect personal data:
Recipient
Purpose of processing
Lawful basis
Data location and security
Personal data collected by the third party
Privacy policy
Matomo Cloud
To collect and analyse information about how you interact with our websites (web analytics), and to recognize and stop any misuse
Legitimate interest
Frankfurt, Germany
Anonymised IP address, Pages visited, browser and device used, mouse movements, anonymised key strokes, and more.
link
Google Recaptcha
To avoid receiving spam emails
Legitimate interest
USA
IP address, Cookie
link
Youtube
Germany
Email address, Username,
Name, Password, Posts
link
Matomo Marketplace shop
To create an account on our shop
Contract
France
Username, Password, Names, Email, Payment information, Phone number Physical address
link
HelpScout
To receive and reply to your messages after you contact us
Legitimate interest
USA
IP address, Message sent, Name, Email…
link
Amazon AWS
USA
Payment transactions details (name, payment details, IP address…)
link
Retention of data
We will retain your information as long as your account is active, as necessary to provide you with the services or as otherwise set forth in this Policy. We will also retain and use this information as necessary for the purposes set out in this Policy and to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements and protect Matomo’s legal rights.
We also collect and maintain aggregated, anonymized or pseudonymized information which we may retain indefinitely to protect the safety and security of our Site, improve our Services or comply with legal obligations.
Privacy Policy Changes
We may update this Policy from time to time. If we do, we’ll let you know about any material changes, either by notifying you on the website or by sending you an email.
Contact Us
E-Mail: privacy@matomo.org
Contact form: matomo.org/contact
EU Representative
Our EU Representative as a controller or processor not established in the Union (article 27 GDPR) is:
ePrivacy Holding GmbH
Große Bleichen 21
20354 Hamburg
Germany
External Data Protection Officer
ePrivacy GmbH
represented by Prof. Dr. Christoph Bauer
Große Bleichen 21, 20354 Hamburg
Germany
If you have any questions or concerns regarding your information, please contact privacy@matomo.org.
If you wish to communicate directly with our data protection officer (because you have a particularly sensitive matter for example), please contact them by post, as communication by e-mail could always have security gaps. Please state in your request that your concern relates to the company InnoCraft.
Reusing this Privacy Policy
Before reading further, please, note that none of our team members are lawyers and do not provide legal or business advice.
You are welcome to reuse and be inspired by this Privacy Policy (published under license CC BY) after making sure it complies with the way your website tracks, uses and discloses users information.
The accuracy, completeness, adequacy of this privacy policy cannot be warranted or guaranteed. Please use it at your own risk.
Learn more in our other pages: Web Analytics & Privacy, List of Features, Matomo supporters and Testimonials. Matomo is a Free Software designed to last.
SupportUser guides
FAQ
Changelog
Glossary
Forums
Developers
Issue tracker
By industry
Sign up for our newsletter
We are constantly adding new features and content to the leading All-In-One Analytics Platform that gives you control over your data. If you want to stay up to date with everything that is happening, feel free to subscribe below.
You can unsubscribe at any time from it. The newsletter service uses MadMimi. Learn more about it within our privacy Policy page.
no thanks
{"cookieName":"wBounce","isAggressive":false,"isSitewide":true,"hesitation":"500","openAnimation":false,"exitAnimation":false,"timer":"","sensitivity":"","cookieExpire":"60","cookieDomain":"","autoFire":"","isAnalyticsEnabled":false}
